纽约市
这就下去协调搜救工作
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
真的  你怎么做到不吐的
I mean, honestly, how do you keep your food down?
闭嘴
Shut up.
伙计
Buddy!
你怎么想的  已达到承载上限了
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
走楼梯吧
Take the stairs.
是啊  别别
Yeah. Stop, stop.
交出箱子  斯塔克
Hand over the case, Stark.
交出来
Hand it over.
斯塔克
Stark?
呼吸
Breathe, breathe.
好样的  巷子里见  我去找点吃的
Good job. Meet me in the alley. I'm gonna grab a quick slice.
不走楼梯
No stairs!
洛基呢
Where's Loki?
洛基  洛基
Loki! Loki!
人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
翻译         恶作剧之草     杏仁斯嘉丽       Eunice
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
时间轴   知之。 大葱   后期   吉吉     校|监    草草
蒙古  戈壁滩
我是阿斯加德的洛基
I am Loki of Asgard.
我肩负光荣的使命
And I am burdened with glorious purpose.
你是谁
你来我们家干什么
我...
I...
没事了
Never mind.
别碰那个
Don't touch that.
似乎是标准的时序违规
Appears to be a standard sequence violation.
时间分支进展速度和斜率稳定
Branch is growing at a stable rate and slope.
时间异体已确认
Variant identified.
你说我什么
I beg your pardon.
代表时间变异管理局
On behalf of the Time Variance Authority,
我以违反神圣时间线的罪名逮捕你
I hereby arrest you for crimes against the Sacred Timeline.
手举起来
Hands up.
你跟我们走
You're coming with us.
抱歉  "我们"是谁
I'm sorry. Who's "Us"?
最后机会  时间异体
Last chance, Variant.
今天真的很辛苦了
It's been a very long day,
我受够了全副武装的白痴
and I think I've had my fill of idiots in armored suits
对我指手画脚
telling me what to do,
所以  不好意思  这其实是你们最后的机会
so, if you don't mind, this is actually your last chance.
给我滚吧
Now get out of my way.
你正在以1/16的速度移动
You are now moving at 1/16th speed,
但却在以实际时间感受疼痛
but feeling all that pain in real time.
重置时间线
Reset the timeline.
-什么种族  -斯库鲁时间异体
- What species? - Variant Skrull.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
我爸可是高盛董事会成员
My dad is on the board of Goldman Sachs.
我一通电话  就让你的工作私有化
One call and your whole job is privatized.
-好了  -你觉得那怎么样
- All right. - How'd you like that?
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
-走了  -你在犯下大错
- Come on. - You're making a terrible mistake.
你犯下了大错
You're making a big mistake.
-你好  长官  -登记这项证物
- Hello, ma'am, uh... - Log this as evidence.
能至少告诉我这是什么吗
Can you at least tell me what it is?
是宇宙魔方  务必小心
It's the Tesseract. Be very careful with it.
听上去好傻
It sounds dumb.
告诉你
Know this.
你敢惹我  后果很严重
You cross me, there are deadly consequences.
走着瞧吧
We'll see.
想都别想
Absolutely not.
这可是高档阿斯加德皮革
This is fine Asgardian leather.
别动
Hold very still.
等一下的
Now, hang on just a minute.
请签字确认这是你说过的所有的话
Please sign to verify this is everything you've ever said.
什么
What?
这个也要签
Sign this, too.
什么
这太荒唐了
Oh, this is absurd.
还有这份
And this.
请确认  据你所知
Please confirm to your knowledge
你并非完全的机械体
that you are not a fully robotic being,
出生时是有机体
were born an organic creature,
并拥有在很多文化中被称为灵魂的东西
and do in fact possess what many cultures would call a soul.
什么  "据我所知"
What? "To my knowledge"?
难道有很多人不知道自己是不是机器人吗
Do a lot of people not know if they're robots?
感谢你的确认  请往前走
Thank you for confirming. Move through.
如果我真是机器人  可我不知道呢
What if I was a robot and I didn't know it?
机器会把你从内熔毁
The machine would melt you from the inside out.
请快走  先生
Please move along, sir.
好吧  我不是机器人  我不会有事
Okay, I'm not a robot, so I'll be fine.
什么
What?
-那是什么  -你的即刻气场
- Oh, what's that? - Your temporal aura.
-那是什么  -请穿过门
- What's that? - Please, through the door.
取号
Take a ticket.
这难道是熟食店吗  不要
What is this, a deli? No.
取号
Take a ticket.
这里只有我们两个
There's only two of us in here.
取号
Take a ticket.
这是个错误  我不该来这里
This is a mistake! I shouldn't be here!
你好  你可能在说
Hey there! You're probably saying,
"这是个错误  我不该来这里"
"This is a mistake. I shouldn't even be here."
欢迎来到时间变异管理局
Welcome to the Time Variance Authority.
我是分钟小姐
I'm Miss Minutes,
我的工作就是在你
and it's my job to catch you up
接受罪行审判前  让你了解情况
before you stand trial for your crimes.
那我们就别再浪费一分钟了
So let's not waste another minute.
坐好  把笔削尖  看看这个吧
Settle in, sharpen your pencils, and check this out.
很久以前  发生了牵涉甚广的多元宇宙战争
Long ago, there was a vast multiversal war.
无数独特的时间线彼此争夺优势地位
Countless unique timelines battled each other for supremacy,
几乎导致了万事万物的
nearly resulting in the total destruction of...
彻底毁灭
...well, everything.
但之后  全知的时间守护者出现了
But then, the all-knowing Time-Keepers emerged,
通过将多元宇宙重新整理为
bringing peace by reorganizing
单一时间线  而带来了和平
the multiverse into a single timeline,
也就是神圣时间线
the Sacred Timeline.
现在时间守护者们
Now, the Time-Keepers
为世上万物保护并保存
protect and preserve the proper flow of time
正常的时间流
for everyone and everything.
但有时  像你这样的人
But sometimes, people like you
会偏离时间守护者创建的道路
veer off the path the Time-Keepers created.
我们称这种人为时间异体
We call those Variants.
或许你发起了起义  或只是上班迟到了
Maybe you started an uprising, or were just late for work.
不管是怎么回事  偏离道路创造了关联事件
Whatever it was, stepping off your path created a nexus event,
关联
如果不加以管理  就可能疯狂分支
which, left unchecked, could branch off into madness,
再次导致多元宇宙战争
leading to another multiversal war.
危险  多元宇宙
但别担心
But, don't worry,
为了确保不会如此
to make sure that doesn't happen,
时间守护者创造了时管局和它了不起的员工们
the Time-Keepers created the TVA and all its incredible workers.
时管局已插手修复了你的错误
The TVA has stepped in to fix your mistake
并让时间恢复到了原本应有的道路上
and set time back on its predetermined path.
而你因为自己的行为
Now that your actions have
在时间线上无容身之地了
left you without a place on the timeline,
所以你必须因自己的罪行受审
you must stand trial for your offenses.
坐好吧  我们会让你马上面见法官
So sit tight, and we'll get you in front of a judge in no time.
务必拿好你的号票
Just make sure you have your ticket,
一旦有接待者有空就会见你
and you'll be seen by the next available attendant.
-时时刻刻  -永永远远
- For all time. - Always.
时间守护者  神圣时间线
Time-Keepers? The Sacred Timeline?
谁会相信这种蠢话
Who actually believes this bunkum?
号票  先生
Ticket, sir?
那人没给我号  我跟他要了
That guy didn't give me a ticket. I tried to ask for one.
-请出示号票  先生  -我还跟他要了
- Ticket, sir! - I tried to ask that guy for a ticket!
先生
Sir...
你还冲我吼起来了吗  蠢货
What, you're raising your voice at me, bucket head?
谢谢您莅临时管局
Thanks for visiting the TVA.
尽请对我们的服务做出评价
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.
洛基
第一季 第一集
法国  普罗旺斯地区艾克斯
追踪者和时间卫队响应了一桩常规关联事件
The hunter and his Minutemen responded to a routine nexus event.
似乎他们到达时  遭到了伏击
It appears that when they arrived, somebody got the jump on 'em.
还用说
You think?
是他
It's him.
是啊  看刺伤跟其他人一致
Yeah, stab wounds look consistent with the others.
尸体的位置
Positioning of the bodies
表明他们根本没来得及反应
indicates they didn't know what the hell hit 'em.
重置设备也不见了
And reset charge is gone.
这是上周第六起袭击了
That's the sixth attack in the last week.
还只是据我们所知
That we know of.
放下武器
Wait, stand down! Stand down.
只是个孩子
It's just a kid.
不好意思
我朋友是个白痴
喂
Hey, yo!
我也会说时间线上的所有语言
混蛋
敲一下
Tap it.
你知道这是谁干的吗
别担心  那个魔鬼还怕我们呢
Don't worry, that devil's afraid of us.
我们会解决他的
We're gonna take care of him.
我们会让你回你该去的地方
And we're gonna put you back where you belong.
那蓝色...
那是怎么回事
爆炸蓝莓口香糖
带礼物来的魔鬼
Devil bearing gifts.
检查它的时序年代
Go ahead and run this for sequence period
和即刻气场痕迹
and any hints of temporal aura.
你知道我们查不到什么的
You know we won't get anything.
就试试嘛
Yeah, just give it a shot.
时间分支接近红线了  我们得走了
The branch is nearing red line. We need to go.
好
Okay.
去外面等着
没事的
It's okay.
进行重置
Set a reset charge.
长官  你会想看看这个
Sir, there's something you'll wanna see.
已被捕
下一案请上前
Next case, please.
劳菲森  时间异体L1130  洛基·劳菲森
Laufeyson. Variant L1130, AKA Loki Laufeyson,
被控时序违规7-20-89
is charged with sequence violation 7-20-89.
你是否认罪
How do you plead?
夫人  神不会恳求
Madam, a god doesn't plead.
这出哑剧还挺有意思
Look, this has been a very enjoyable pantomime,
但我现在想回家了
but I'd like to go home now.
你是否有罪  先生
Are you guilty or not guilty, sir?
我可是恶作剧之神  是的
Guilty of being the God of Mischief? Yes.
我是否觉得这一切无比乏味  是的
Guilty of finding all this incredibly tedious? Yes.
是否违反了神圣时间线
Guilty of a crime against the Sacred Timeline?
绝对没有  你们抓错了人
Absolutely not, you have the wrong person.
是吗  那我们该抓谁去
Oh, really? And who should we have?
我怀疑是复仇者联盟
I suspect, the Avengers.
我之所以能拿到宇宙魔方
You see, I only came into possession of the Tesseract
是因为他们穿越了时间
because they traveled through time,
肯定是为阻止我登天为神王
no doubt in a last-ditch effort to
而做出的最后一搏
stave off my ascent to God King.
好严重的指控
That's quite an accusation.
相信我  两个托尼·斯塔克的古龙水味儿好明显
Oh, believe me, you can smell the cologne of two Tony Starks.
你说什么时间罪犯  那你该去找他们
You speak of Time Criminals? It's they you should be after.
或许你可以给我指派一支特遣队  再给我些资源
Perhaps you could provide me with a taskforce and resources,
我可以回去  替你们除掉他们
and I could return and eliminate them for you.
我们要说的不是复仇者联盟
We're not here to talk about the Avengers.
-是吗  -对
- Oh, no? - No.
他们做的事本就该发生  而你的逃跑不是
What they did was supposed to happen. You escaping was not.
这样啊
Right.
"不该发生"  这谁说的
"Not supposed to happen"? According to whom?
时间守护者啊
The Time-Keepers?
时间守护者  这样啊
Oh, the Time-Keepers. Right.
或许我该跟这些时间守护者  神对神地谈谈
Well, perhaps I should speak to these Time-Keepers, gods to gods.
抱歉  但他们很忙呢
I'm sorry, but they're quite busy.
是吗  他们忙着干什么呢
Oh, they are? What are they doing?
决定正常的时间流
Dictating the proper flow of time.
这样啊  好吧  那你是做什么的
I see. Right. And then what do you do?
按照他们的决定  决定正常的时间流
Dictate the proper flow of time according to their dictations.
你是否认罪
How do you plead?
我的确
Guilty...
做了这个
of this.
-怎么回事  -等等  都别说话
- What's going on? - Hang on. Everyone quiet.
-他是想用他的法力  夫人  -别催我
- He's trying to use his powers, ma'am. - Don't rush me.
该死  怎么不好使
Damn it! Why won't it work?
魔法吗  那个在时管局不能用  劳菲森先生
Magic powers? They're no good in the TVA, Mr. Laufeyson.
本庭判你有罪  我判你被重置
The court finds you guilty, and I sentence you to be reset.
下一案请上前
Next case, please!
"重置"  那什么意思
"Reset"? What does that mean?
那很糟吗  那什么意思
What, is it bad? What does it mean?
你们这些荒唐的官僚
You ridiculous bureaucrats
休想决定我的故事如何结局
will not dictate how my story ends!
不是你的故事  劳菲森先生  从来都不是
It's not your story, Mr. Laufeyson. It never was.
你根本想象不到我能做什么
You have no idea what I'm capable of!
我可能知道
I... I think I might.
他能做什么
Have an idea of what he's capable of.
上前
Approach the bench.
如果你在想我认为你在想的那事  那不是好主意
If you're thinking what I think you are, it's a bad idea.
好吧  我只是跟着直觉走
Okay, I'm just chasing a hunch.
如果出了任何岔子  都怪在你头上
Anything goes sideways, it's on you.
好  我觉得我总在仰视你
Okay. I feel like I'm always looking up to you.
我喜欢  很恰当
I like it. It's appropriate.
你是谁
And who are you?
我要把这里烧成灰
I'm gonna burn this place to the ground.
我带你去我的办公桌  你从那里开始烧吧
I'll show you where my desk is, you can start there.
看看吧
Have a look.
美丽的家园
Home sweet home.
这里不是没有魔法吗
I thought there was no magic here.
是没有
There isn't.
那不是真的
That's not real.
是的  很遗憾  各种文件也是真的
It is, and, unfortunately, so is all the paperwork.
但可以给你点火做火绒  来吧
Good tinder for your fire, though. Come on.
这地方是个噩梦
This place is a nightmare.
那是另一个部门了
That's another department.
那个部门我乐意帮你烧光
Now that department I'll help you burn down.
对了  我是莫比乌斯特工
I'm Agent Mobius, by the way.
你是要带我去个什么地方杀掉吗
Are you taking me somewhere to kill me?
不是  我才带你离开那个处境
No. That's where you just were.
我的带你去个地方谈谈
I'm taking you some place to talk.
我不喜欢谈谈
I don't like to talk.
但你喜欢撒谎  你刚刚还撒了谎
But you do like to lie, which you just did.
因为我们都知道  你很喜欢说话
Because we both know you love to talk.
说啊说啊
Talkie-talkie.
你在这里干多久了
How long have you been here?
我不知道  不好说
I don't know. It's hard to say,
时管局的时间流逝不一样
time passes differently here in the TVA.
-什么意思  -你会了解的
- What does that mean? - You'll catch up.
所以你是时管局勇敢尽心的员工之一吗
So, you're part of the TVA's courageous and dedicated workforce?
对
Yes.
-你们是时间守护者创造的  -对
- You were created by the Time- Keepers. - Yep.
-目的是保护神圣时间线  -对
- To protect the Sacred Timeline. - Correct.
那好笑吗
Is that funny?
你们的小俱乐部
The idea that your little club
能代表三个太空蜥蜴
decides the fate of trillions of people
决定浩瀚宇宙中无数人的命运
across all of existence at the behest of three space lizards,
是的  这很好笑
yes, it's funny.
这好荒唐
It's absurd.
不是说你不喜欢说话吗
I thought you didn't like to talk.
你先请
After you.
我要说
For the record,
这里感觉真像用来杀我的房间
this really does feel like a killing-me kind of a room.
不怎么信任人  是吧
Not big on trust, are you?
孩子和狗才会信任
Trust is for children and dogs.
你只能信任一个人
There's only one person you can trust.
你自己吗  我喜欢
Yourself? I like it.
印T恤衫吧
Slap it on a T-shirt.
如果时管局真的监管一切时间
If the TVA truly oversees all of time,
我们怎么会此前都没听说过你们
how have I never heard of you until now?
因为你此前不需要听说
'Cause you've never needed to.
你一直生活在你的既定道路里
You've always lived within your set path.
我是生活在我选择的道路里
I live within whatever path I choose.
当然了  好了  来坐吧
Sure you do. Okay, come have a seat.
我说了  时管局的时间运行不一样
I told you, time moves differently in the TVA.
来坐吧
Come on, sit down.
我们开始吧
Let's get into this.
来啊  坐吧
Go on, have a seat.
要是眼神能杀人
If looks could kill.
你想要我怎么样
What do you want from me?
先配合一下吧
Well, let's start with a little cooperation.
我不擅长
Not my forte.
是吗
Really?
哪怕是讨好你打算背叛的强者时吗
Even when you're wooing someone powerful you intend to betray?
得了
Come on.
你根本不了解我
You don't know anything about me.
或许我想了解呢
Maybe I'd like to learn.
我专门追踪危险的时间异体
I specialize in the pursuit of dangerous Variants.
比如我吗
Like myself?
不  是特别危险的时间异体
No, particularly dangerous Variants.
你就是个小猫咪
You're just a little pussycat.
我要问你一组问题
I got a set of questions for you.
你要诚实回答
You answer them honestly,
那样的话  我或许能满足你的一些愿望
and then maybe I can give you something you want.
你想离开这里  是吧
You wanna get out of here, right?
嗯  那就从这里开始
Yeah, so we'll start there.
如果你回去了  打算怎么做
Should you return, what are you gonna do?
-完成我开启的大业  -那是什么
- Finish what I started. - Which is?
夺取我的王位
Claim my throne.
你想做国王吗
You wanna be king?
我不是想做  我生来就是
I don't want to be, I was born to be.
我知道  但具体是什么的国王
I know, but king of what exactly?
你不会理解的
You wouldn't understand.
说来试试
Try me.
米德加德
Midgard.
就是地球
AKA Earth.
好  你成为米德加德的国王了  然后呢
All right. Now you're the king of Midgard, then what?
幸福永远了吗
Happily ever after?
阿斯加德  九大王国
Asgard, the Nine Realms.
-宇宙吗  -什么
- Space? - Space?
宇宙很大  那是不错的功绩
Space is big. That'd be a nice feather in your cap.
"洛基  宇宙之王"
"Loki, the King of Space."
你敢嘲笑我
Mock me if you dare.
不  我没
No, I'm not.
真的  我其实是你的粉丝
Honestly, I'm actually a fan. Yeah.
我就是在想
And I guess I'm wondering why
你这么有潜力的人  怎么就想做统治者
does someone with so much range just wanna rule?
我会让人们轻松的
I would've made it easy for them.
人们喜欢轻松
People like easy.
第一个  也是最压迫的谎言
The first and most oppressive lie ever uttered
就是自由之歌
was the song of freedom.
怎么说
How's that one go?
对几乎所有生灵
For nearly every living thing,
选择带来羞耻  不确定和后悔
choice breeds shame and uncertainty and regret.
每条道路上都有岔路
There's a fork in every road,
可人们总走错路
yet the wrong path always taken.
很好
Good. Yeah.
你说"几乎所有生灵"
You said "Nearly every living thing,"
那么你应该是不算在内咯
so I'm guessing you don't fall into that category?
时间守护者建造了惊人的奇景
The Time-Keepers have built quite the circus,
而且小丑也完美地扮演了自己的角色
and I see the clowns are playing their parts to perfection.
这么爱用比喻  我喜欢
Big metaphor guy. I love it.
让你听上去特别聪明
Makes you sound super smart.
我就是聪明
I am smart.
我知道
I know.
好
Okay.
这是什么
What is this?
你壮举的抽样  容我来
A sampling of your greatest hits, if I may.
如果你们不介意
If it's all the same to you...
我现在想来一杯
I'll have that drink now.
不用
No.
我记得  我当时也在  还有吗
And I remember. I was there. Anything else?
真有趣  生来的统治者  你输了好多次
It's funny, for someone born to rule, you sure do lose a lot.
甚至可以说这是你的天性
You might even say it's in your nature.
上一个对我说这种话的人
You know, things didn't turn out so well
下场可不怎么好
for the last person who said that to me.
嗯  菲尔·科尔森
Oh, yeah, Phil Coulson.
不
No!
复仇者联盟不是为了
Didn't the Avengers come together
给他复仇而团结一心  击败了你吗
to literally avenge him by defeating you?
对于一个死人算不上什么安慰了
Little solace to a dead man.
你喜欢伤人吗
Do you enjoy hurting people?
让他们觉得渺小
Making them feel small?
让他们感到恐惧
Making them feel afraid?
-你的游戏吓不倒我  -让他们觉得弱小
- Your games don't frighten me. - Making them feel little?
我知道我是什么人
I know what I am.
-杀人犯吗  -解放者
- A murderer? - A liberator.
解放了眼球吧
Of eyeballs, maybe.
看那笑容  你很喜欢那么做
Look at that smile. You are enjoying that.
你喜欢伤害他们吗
Did you enjoy hurting them?
我不需要玩这种游戏  我可是神
I don't have to play this game. I'm a god.
什么神来着  恶作剧之神吧
Of what, again? Mischief, right?
嗯  我可不觉得这算什么恶作剧
Yeah. I don't see anything very mischievous about this.
是啊  你是看不出吧
No, I don't suppose you do.
我们谈谈你的逃跑吧
Let's talk about your escapes.
你很擅长做坏事
You're really good at doing awful things,
然后逃掉
and then just getting away.
没办法  我就是个喜欢恶作剧的顽皮鬼
What can I say? I'm a mischievous scamp.
这是我最喜欢的之一
This is one of my favorites.
这里是驾驶舱  威廉·A·斯考特机长
From the flight deck, Captain William A. Scott,
西北东方航空305航班  按时飞往西雅图
Northwest Orient Airlines 305, on schedule to land in Seattle.
今天的飞行时间  约...
Flight time today, approximately...
波本和苏打水吗
Bourbon and soda?
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
Absolutely.
还需要我为您做什么吗  先生
Is there anything else I can do for you, sir?
那就看看吧
I suppose we'll find out, won't we?
-小姐  -是  库珀先生
- Uh, Miss? - Yes, Mr. Cooper?
你最好看看那张字条
You might want to take a look at that note.
我有枚炸弹
I have a bomb.
我看不出这有什么关系...
I fail to see how this has any relevance or bearing on...
别  精彩的部分在这里
No. This is the good part.
改天再见了
See you again someday.
哥哥  海姆达尔  你们最好准备好了
Brother, Heimdall, you better be ready.
真不敢相信你是DB·库珀  拜托
I can't believe you were D.B. Cooper. Come on!
我当时还年轻  打赌输给了托尔
I was young, and I lost a bet to Thor.
我插手这样的人间事务时  时管局怎么不管
Where was the TVA when I was meddling with these affairs of men?
我们当时也在  在神圣时间线上冲浪呢
We were right there with you, just surfing that Sacred Timeline.
所以那就得到了时间守护者的认同吗
So that had the Time-Keepers' seal of approval, did it?
说起来倒不算是
Well, I wouldn't think of it
认同或不认同
in terms of approval and disapproval.
那是...
That's sort of a...
我们继续说逃跑吧
Let's get back to escapes...
以及心理问题
...and a little psychobabble.
你觉得你究竟在逃离什么
What is it that you think that you're really running from?
够了
Enough.
回笼子里咯
Back in your cage.
看  我也会玩狠的
See, I can play the heavy keys, too.
我站起来只是有话说
I was just standing up to make a point.
抱歉  请吧
I'm sorry, go ahead.
现在做就失去意义了
It won't be as meaningful now.
好吧  那坐着别动
Okay, well, stay seated.
我想做什么就做什么
I'll do what I want to do!
当然
Sure.
你到底想怎么样
What exactly is it that you want?
我想要你坦诚你这样做的原因
I want you to be honest about why you do what you do.
骗子
Liar.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我只想更深入地了解
All I seek is a deeper understanding
可怕的恶作剧之神
of the fearsome God of Mischief.
洛基的动机是什么
What makes Loki tick?
-我知道这是什么地方  -什么地方
- I know what this place is. - What is it?
这是个幻象
It's an illusion.
是弱者
It's a cruel,
为了激发恐惧而精心策划的残忍诡计
elaborate trick conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
孤注一掷  试图掌控一切
A desperate attempt at control.
你们招摇卖弄
Now, you all parade about
仿佛你们是宇宙力量的神圣仲裁者
as if you're the divine arbiters of power in the universe.
-我们的确是  -才不是
- We are. - You're not.
我的选择是我自己的
My choices are my own.
你的选择是你自己的  很好  就从这儿入手
Your choice is your own. Good, let's go with that.
这应该能让你激动起来
I think this one's gonna fire you up.
自由的光鲜诱惑削减了你们人生的乐趣
The bright lure of freedom diminishes your life's joy
让你们发狂地追逐权力
in a mad scramble for power...
确实
Precisely.
我本来...
I was...
我现在仍然快要得到我应得的一切
I am on the verge of acquiring everything I am owed,
如果我得到了  都是因为我的努力
and when I do, it'll be because I did it.
不是因为这本就该发生
Not because it was supposed to happen.
也不是因为你或时间变异管理局
Or because you or the Time Variance Authority,
或不管你们自称什么  允许我得到
or whatever it is you call yourselves, allowed me to.
老实说  你很可悲
Honestly, you're pathetic.
你无关紧要
You're an irrelevance.
只是一条弯路
A detour.
我攀登的注脚
A footnote to my ascent.
你说完了吗
You finished?
你要开始严肃对待了
You're gonna start taking things seriously.
如果你那时没有捡起宇宙魔方
If you hadn't picked up the Tesseract,
你就会被关进阿斯加德的牢房
you would have been taken to a cell on Asgard.
洛基
Loki.
你好  母亲
Hello, Mother.
你为我骄傲吗
Have I made you proud?
求求你  别让事情变得更糟
Please don't make this worse.
这是什么
What is this?
这是胡扯  又是幻术  这根本没发生过
This is nonsense, more tricks. This never even happened.
没发生在你身上
Not to you.
还没有
Not yet.
时管局不止知道你的过去
Look, the TVA doesn't just know your whole past,
我们还知道你的一生  注定要发生的一切
we know your whole life, how it's all meant to be.
把这看作安慰
Think of it as comforting.
这太荒谬了
This is absurd.
那我也不是你母亲吗
And am I not your mother?
不是
You're not.
你总能看透一切  却看不透自己
Always so perceptive about everyone but yourself.
然后黑暗精灵袭击了宫殿
And then the Dark Elves attack the palace,
你以为你让他们去找托尔了
and you think you send them to Thor.
走左边的楼梯吧
You might wanna take the stairs to the left.
其实你把他们指向了...
But instead, you send them...
我绝不会告诉你
I'll never tell.
你把她关在哪了  她在哪里
Where do you have her? Where is she?
你让他们找到了她
You lead them right to her.
我不相信  你撒谎  这不是真的
I don't believe you. You're lying. It's not true.
这就是真的
It is true.
那才是正常的时间流
That's the proper flow of time,
它一次又一次发生
and it happens again and again and again
因为理应如此
because it's supposed to,
因为必须如此
because it has to.
-时管局确保了  -她在哪里
- The TVA makes sure of it. - Where is she?
不如你告诉我  你喜欢伤人吗
Now why don't you tell me, do you enjoy hurting people?
-我不信你  -你享受杀戮吗
- I don't believe you. - Do you enjoy killing?
-我要杀了你  -就像你杀了你妈妈
- I'll kill you. - What? Like you did your mother?
抱歉  时间扭转器只让你循环
Sorry, the Time Twister just loops you,
对椅子不起作用
not the furniture.
你并非生来注定为王  洛基
You weren't born to be king, Loki.
而是注定带来痛苦  苦难和死亡
You were born to cause pain and suffering and death.
现在如此  过去如此  将来也如此
That's how it is, that's how it was, that's how it will be.
都是为了让其他人能成就最好的自己
All so that others can achieve their best versions of themselves.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
来吧
Come on.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我的工作  你的工作是来打断吗
My job. Is it yours to interrupt?
有情况
We have a situation.
总是有情况
There's always a situation.
哪都别去
Don't go anywhere.
正进行到精彩的地方  情绪高昂
It was just getting good. Spirited.
-和那个时间异体对话是个错误  -那是你的看法
- Talking to that Variant is a mistake. - That's your position.
-他应该被重置  -我的观点与你相反
- He should be reset! - I take the opposite...
你认为所有人都该被重置  我刚取得进展
You think everyone should be reset. I'm getting good stuff!
我们又失去了一支队伍
We lost another unit.
洛基  我们明天再完成  接着...
Okay, Loki, I think we can finish up tomorrow and just pick it...
恶作剧的顽皮鬼
Mischievous scamp.
可惜我不感到意外
Wish I could say I was surprised.
-谁让你打断了我们  -我  怪我咯
- Yeah, I wish you hadn't interrupted us. - Me? It's my fault?
听着  他一定没走远
Look, he can't have gotten very far.
分头行动  见人就删
Split up. Prune on sight.
不  不准删除或重置  他仍能帮我们
No, no pruning, no resetting. He can still help us!
我知道你
I know you.
你是那个带着蓝盒子的罪犯
You're that criminal with the blue box.
你叫什么
What's your name?
凯西
Casey.
把宇宙魔方给我  否则我把你当鱼一样开膛  凯西
Give me the Tesseract, or I'll gut you like a fish, Casey.
鱼是什么
What's a fish?
鱼是什么东西
你怎么会不知道鱼是什么
How do you not know what a fish is?
我这辈子一直坐在桌子后面
I've lived my entire life behind a desk.
那又如何
Well, what difference does it make?
我想知道我面对的是什么威胁  然后再照办
I wanna know exactly what I'm being threatened with before I comply.
死亡  凯西  暴力的痛苦的死亡
Death, Casey. Violent, painful death.
好好好  我照办
Okay, okay. I comply, I comply.
我照办  天啊
I comply. Jeez!
是这个
This it?
什么
What?
无限宝石
Infinity Stones?
你怎么
How...
你怎么拿到它们的
How do you have these?
我们有很多
Oh, We actually get a lot of those.
对  有人用这些石头当镇纸
Yeah. Some of the guys use them as paperweights.
有些人吧
Some of 'em.
这是宇宙里最强大的力量吗
Is this the greatest power in the universe?
你差点打到我
Oh, you almost hit me!
太过分了
That's so messed up.
分头行动  搜查下面的大厅
Split up. Check the lower concourse.
我不原谅你
I do not forgive you.
我爱你们  我的儿子
I love you, my sons.
记住这地方
Remember this place.
家园
Home.
洛基  我曾非常看重你
Loki, I thought the world of you.
我以为我们能永远并肩战斗
I thought we were gonna fight side by side forever.
或许你也没那么坏  弟弟
Maybe you're not so bad after all, brother.
或许吧
Maybe not.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你真在这里  我或许还会抱抱你
If you were here, I might even give you a hug.
我在这儿
I'm here.
不死
Undying?
你措辞该更小心点的
You should choose your words more carefully.
你
You...
永远不会成为
will never be...
神
a god.
文件结束
什么事这么好笑
What's so funny?
光荣的使命
Glorious purpose.
停
Stop...
下来
It.
停下来
Stop it!
St... Stop it...
下来  停下来
It... Stop it...
停  下来  停下来
Stop... I... St... Sto... St...
那人一直念叨着要把我变成鱼
And this guy kept saying he was gonna turn me into a fish,
不知道那是什么
whatever that is,
然后他们出现了  删了我的推车
and then they show up and just prune my cart,
所以我什么都做不了
so there was nothing I could have done.
你在这儿啊
There you are.
你之前抓的那个时间异体溜走了
You know, that Variant you had got away.
洛基
Loki?
无处可逃了哦
Nowhere left to run.
我不能回去  对吧
I can't go back, can I?
不能回我的时间线
Back to my timeline.
我不喜欢伤害人
I don't enjoy hurting people.
我
I...
我不喜欢
I don't enjoy it.
我那样做也是无奈
I do it because I have to,
因为我当时不得不那样做
because I've had to.
跟我详细说说
Okay, explain that to me.
因为那是幻象的一部分
Because it's part of the illusion.
是弱者为了激发恐惧
It's the cruel, elaborate trick
而精心策划的残忍诡计
conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
孤注一掷  试图掌控一切
A desperate play for control.
你相当了解你自己嘛
You do know yourself.
一个恶棍
A villain.
我不这么看
That's not how I see it.
你想用它
You try to use that?
用过几次
Oh, several times.
就连无限宝石在这里都没用了
Even an Infinity Stone is useless here.
时管局如此强大
The TVA is formidable.
从我的经验来看  没错
That's been my experience.
听着  我给不了你救赎
Listen, I can't offer you salvation,
但我也许可以给你更好的
but maybe I can offer you something better.
一名在逃时间异体一直在杀害我们的时间卫队
A fugitive Variant's been killing our Minutemen.
你们需要恶作剧之神协助你们阻止他
And you need the God of Mischief to help you stop him?
没错
That's right.
那为什么选我
Why me?
我们要抓捕的时间异体是
The Variant we're hunting is...
你
you.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
俄克拉荷马  萨林那
时间特征是3000年初
Time signature is early third millennium.
绝对不属于这个时代
Definitely anachronistic.
石油
Oil.
应该是哪个混蛋找到了一台时间机器
I think some jackass found himself a time machine,
回来过去  想要暴富
came back here to get rich.
要我们散开找他吗  长官
Should we fan out and look for him, sir?
不了  不值得我们写报告
Nah. It's not worth the paperwork.
删了它  我们撤  进行重置
Just prune it. Let's bail. Set a charge.
等等  那边有人
Wait. Someone's out there.
去看看
Check it out.
趴下
Get down!
谢谢您莅临时管局
Thanks for visiting the TVA.
尽请对我们的服务做出评价
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.